Hi there! I hope you're ready to start using Python to visualize your data.
大家好 希望你们已经准备好用 Python 来可视化数据了
In this course, we will use NumPy and Pandas to store our data
本课将使用 NumPy 和 Pandas 来存放数据
it will use matplotlib Seaborn to create our visualizations.
用 Matplotlib 和 Seaborn 来创建可视化图表
You might see the abbreviation SNS for Seaborne but I'll be using SB In this course.
你可能见过 seaborn 的另一个缩写 sns 但本课要用的缩写是 sb
We will also write and run all of our code using Jupyter Notebooks.
而且本课所有代码都会用 Jupyter Notebook 来编写和运行
This magic command percent sign matplotlib inline
使用这个魔法命令 (magic command) %matplotlib inline
allows plots to be rendered directly inside the notebook.
我们就能直接在 notebook 里绘制图表了
In this lesson, we're going to make use of this dataset
本课要使用的数据集
comprised of attributes of creatures in the video game series Pokemon.
记录了精灵宝可梦系列游戏的角色数据
The dataset consists of 807 rows by
数据集共有 807 行14 列
14 columns which include both categorical and numeric features.
既有分类变量也有数值变量
To start off with, let's create a bar chart on one of
我们先取数据集的一个分类变量 generation_id
the categorical variables in the dataset, generation ID.
创建条形图
Even though the values in the column look numeric,
虽然这一列的值看起来像数字
they're actually just categorical labels indicating when each species
但实际上是分类标签 表示各种宝可梦是在
was introduced to the series from first generation to seventh generation.
游戏哪一代被引入的 (游戏共有七代)
To create a bar chart, we want to make use of the Seaborn function, countplot.
要创建条形图 可用 seaborn 的 countplot 函数
We set the data source,
参数 data 代表数据来源
the Pokemon dataframe on the data parameter and
我们将其设为 DataFrame pokemon
the variable of interest the generation ID column on the x parameter.
设参数 x 为目标变量 generation_id
It's not absolutely necessary but I've added a semicolon to the end of
我在语句最后加了分号 不过这不是严格必须的
the expression to suppress printing of the plotting object information.
加了分号 图表绘制对象的信息就不会显示出来了
We can see from the plot that the most Pokemon were introduced in generations one,
由图可知 大多数宝可梦都是在第一代、
three and five with the fewest in generations six, seven.
第三代和第五代引入的 而第六代和第七代则是宝可梦引入最少的两代
One thing that bothers me about the default settings is
默认设置有一点不好
that each bar is illustrated using a different color.
那就是条形颜色各不相同
The generation number is already encoded by position on the x-axis and we
x 轴已经表明了是游戏的第几代
don't have a good reason right now to associate each generation with a different color.
没必要用不同的颜色再来表明不同的代数
It's better to start by plotting everything in one color to avoid being distracted.
因此 为了避免分散注意力 我们最好只用一种颜色
I will obtain my color value using Seaborn's color palette function.
我用 seaborn 的color_palette 函数来获取颜色值
This function returns a list of tuples corresponding
该函数会根据参数的设置
to the color pallet set in the function's arguments.
返回一个颜色元组的列表
Since I haven't specified any parameters,
由于我没有指定参数
I'll just get back the current default palate.
所以函数会返回现在的默认色板
Since I just want one color,
因为我只想要一种颜色
I'm going to slice off index zero to get the first tuple in
所以我用索引 0 进行切片 取得列表的第一个元素
the list and I'm going to store that in the base color variable.
并将其赋给变量 base_color
Then, in the countplot function,
然后在函数 countplot 中
I'm going to set the value of the color parameter to the tuple.
把颜色参数 color 的值设为该颜色值
The revised plot looks like this. Much cleaner.
修改后效果如图 干净多了
One thing we might want to do with the plot now is to sort
现在我们可能想
the generations in order by number of Pokemon species that were introduced.
根据每一代引入的宝可梦种类数量来给各代排序
This can be done with the order parameter in the countplot function.
因此我们可以在函数 countplot 中使用参数 order
This parameter takes as an argument a list
这个参数接受一个列表
with the order in which bars should be plotted.
即各个条形的排序列表
We could approach this by hard coding
因此我们可以根据目前尚未排序的图表
the values based on what we see in the unsorted plot.
对相应的值进行硬编码
So, for example, we could start here with five and end was six.
比如 我们可以先输入 5 以此类推 最后输入 6
A better approach is to write some code to obtain that order programmatically.
但更好的办法是编写代码 让程序自动排序
The pandas series function value counts is valuable here.
而这就是 pandas series 的 value_counts 函数派上用场的时候了
This function counts the frequency of
该函数会统计
each unique value in the series and then sort them in descending order.
Series 唯一值的频率 并进行降序排列
In order to get the bar order,
为了给条形排序
we want the index values and then,
我们得获取索引 (.index)
store them in a variable.
并将这些索引赋给一个变量
We pass this to the order parameter in order to get the sorted bar chart.
将该变量传递给 order 参数实现对条形的排序
Let's move on to a different categorical variable, Pokemon type.
我们来看另一个分类变量 宝可梦的属性
Each species has one or two types that play
每种宝可梦都有一到两种属性
a part in each creature's offensive and defensive capabilities.
与其攻击、防御能力有关
For now, let's just take a look at the distribution of first Pokemon types.
我们先来看第一个属性 (type_1) 的分布
When we generate the bar chart,
生成条形图
we can see that the bar labels on the x axis are mostly unreadable due to overlap.
不难发现 x 轴上的标签重叠了 难以阅读
One thing that we might do is make use of
我们可以使用
matplotlib's Xticks function to rotate the category labels.
matplotlib 的 xticks 函数来旋转类别标签
By setting rotation equals 90,
将旋转度 rotation 设为 90
the labels are turned 90 degrees counterclockwise and no longer overlap.
标签就会逆时针旋转 90 度 不再相互重叠了
An alternative strategy is to create a horizontal bar chart.
我们也可以创建横向条形图来解决这个问题
In Seaborn, this is as simple as changing the x parameter into a Y.
在 seaborn 里 要实现这一点 只需将参数 x 改为 y 即可
Now, the levels of the type variable are listed on
这样属性变量的类别就落在了纵轴上
the vertical axis with frequency shown on the X axis.
频率则落在了 x 轴上
Once we sort the plot by type frequency,
根据属性频率对图表进行排序
we can see that water and normal types are the most common first type
我们就可以看到第一属性为水系和一般系的宝可梦最多
taken by Pokemon while flying is the least common first type.
飞行系的则最少